var quiz = [{"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Natural hazards are those in which there is no human presence or impact."}, {"answers": ["adaptation to changes", "the precautionary principle", "trial-and-error", "the rule of experts"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "In cultural theory, egalitarians are likely to use _______ as a risk approach."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Cultural theory argues that perception of risk is based on how we interact with others, rather than universal human traits or individual biases."}, {"answers": ["lead to environmental degradation in poor neighborhoods.", "force people to choose between unemployment and work hazards.", "limit people\u2019s ability to make informed decisions.", "all of the choices given are correct/true."], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "Environmental justice movements attempt to correct systemic inequalities that"}, {"answers": ["Change zoning laws to prevent more people from living in flood-prone areas.", "Increase insurance premiums for homes and businesses in flood-prone areas.", "The use of engineering efforts to control flooding, like levees.", "White would recommend a combination of all of the choices given in this question, since there is no way to eliminate risk by implementing just one of the options given."], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "Gilbert F. White would suggest which of the following methods to control flooding on the Mississippi River?"}, {"answers": ["the estimated likelihood that a decision or action will have a negative consequence.", "the degree to which probabilities cannot be assessed.", "the tendency of people to evaluate the hazardousness of a situation or decision based on biases.", "a product, process, or condition that potentially threatens people and their reproduction."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Risk is defined as"}, {"answers": ["Egalitarians", "Hierarchists", "Individualists", "Fatalists"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Under cultural theory, which group would view nature as being fragile?"}, {"answers": ["view nature as resilient.", "assume that disturbances to natural systems are only temporary.", "endorse the consumption of genetically modified organisms.", "prefer to avoid certain activities until it is clear that they are safe."], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "A culture that espouses the precautionary principle is likely to:"}, [["In a local casino, the poker dealer can choose whether to be exposed to cigarette smoke and keep his or her job, or not take the job.", "Constraints on decisions"], ["The dangers of unprotected sex are well publicized on packages of contraceptives.", "None of the other choices"], ["In Oregon, Ohio, the oil refinery is located adjacent to poorer communities that have little voice in the quality of emissions coming from the plant.", "Control of decisions"], ["An asteroid is headed toward Earth. The government chooses not to let the public know because people will panic and make things worse.\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0", "Control of information"], ["Constraints on decisions", "None of the other choices", "Control of decisions", "Control of information"]], {"answers": ["not taking consequences into consideration", "controllability of risk", "potential for catastrophe", "choice in exposure to risk"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Which of the following factors does NOT influence risk perception?"}, {"answers": ["hard-wired through evolution.", "learned through socialization and culture.", "based only on individual interactions with the environment.", "irrational because it is based on affect."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Douglas and other cultural theorists suggest that our sense of hazards, risk, and uncertainty is"}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Gilbert F. White argued that engineering technologies such as levees were the solution to flooding problems."}, {"answers": ["True", "False"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The more we advance technologically, the more uncertain risks become."}, {"answers": ["the precautionary principle", "trial-and-error", "adaptation to changes", "the rule of experts"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "In cultural theory, fatalists are likely to use _______ as a risk approach."}, {"answers": ["Instability of systems.", "Encounters with new hazards.", "Uneven behavior of environmental systems.", "Systems basically function the same everywhere."], "correctIndex": 3, "question": "Which if the following is NOT a source of uncertainty?"}, {"answers": ["voluntary", "potential for catastrophe", "unobservable", "immediate effects"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Which of the following risk perception biases is likely to lead to an underestimation of risk?"}, {"answers": ["Individualists", "Hierarchists", "Fatalists", "Egalitarians"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Under cultural theory, which group would view nature as being resilient?"}, {"answers": ["People always fit into only one of the four categories based on their personal views.", "Shows us that risk perception is cultural and political and not based on individual psychology.", "Presents a problem as people don\u2019t always fit into one group at a time, or can shift groups over time.", "Provides security against one-track solutions for society as a whole."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true of cultural theory?"}, {"answers": ["uncertainty", "vulnerability", "hazard", "risk"], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "The degree to which the outcomes of a situation are unknown is called"}, {"answers": ["risk, hazard, uncertainty", "uncertainty, hazard, risk", "hazard, risk, uncertainty", "hazard, uncertainty, risk"], "correctIndex": 2, "question": "The _____ is the danger, ______ is the probability that the danger will occur, and ______ is the degree to which we do not know whether that danger will occur."}, {"answers": ["To find the source of the problem.", "To judge whether consequences are great enough to require increased regulation.", "To estimate how much damage can be expected.", "To determine whether a behavior or process should be allowed to continue based on the benefits vs. the risk."], "correctIndex": 0, "question": "Risk assessments are conducted for all of the following reasons, EXCEPT:"}, {"answers": ["No hazards are completely natural as there are indirect human influences.", "Hazards only exist where humans do not have some vested interest.", "Human-induced climate change could be contributing to hazards like hurricanes.", "Human presence alone creates hazards."], "correctIndex": 1, "question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true regarding humans and hazards?"}, [["You can see evidence that your sexual partner has an STD infection. How might this influence your perception of the risk of catching an STD?", "Underestimate Risk"], ["You learn that asbestos as been found at your workplace. You need this job and can\u2019t quit right now. How would your knowledge of this influence your perception of the risk for going to work?", "Overestimate Risk"], ["One might think most car crashes are the result of poor drivers. Because you know you are an excellent driver, how would this influence your perception of risk in choosing to drive a car?", "Underestimate Risk"], ["You know of several, well publicized air plane crashes where no one walked away alive. How does this influence your perception of risk for airplane travel?", "Overestimate Risk"], ["People that smoke only get cancer or other diseases when they are much older it seems. How would this thinking affect your perception of risk for choosing to smoke?", "Underestimate Risk"], ["Underestimate Risk", "Overestimate Risk"]]]

quizCollection['6'] = quiz
